<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-web on mnml.blog</title>
    <link>https://mnml.blog/tags/open-web/</link>
    <description>mnml.blog (open-web)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 01:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://mnml.blog/tags/open-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making This Site My Knowledge Store</title>
      <author>James Evans</author>
      <link>https://mnml.blog/2021/01/making-this-site-my-knowledge-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnml.blog/2021/01/making-this-site-my-knowledge-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I posted to this blog 264 times in 2020. That is significantly more than in any previous year. I hope to post even more this year. I know that is easier said than done but I have a plan. I’m going to make this website the central repository for more of my knowledge, interests, and hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so easy to accumulate digital information and I collect it in many different ways. I am going to start putting things here first and I will consolidate old information to the site as I use it. I hope that makes it easier for me to find things in the future and I also hope that it benefits some of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by an old but still relevant talk by Scott Hanselman at Webstock 2012, “It’s Not What You Read, It’s What You Ignore”. I’ve embedded the video below. This is a hilarious presentation. It is worth watching multiple times. It is dense with useful information. One point that sticks with me is the idea that we only have a finite number of keystrokes. Rather than waste them in closed silos, we should use our blogs as multipliers of our keystrokes. That gets back to what the internet should be, at least in my opinion. It should be an open platform that democratizes information and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/39020426?dnt=1&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>